Welcome all of you to the brand new video of this academy from Sone. Our Tom
Plant video has received a great response
from you all and in its comment section
you had requested that I
make a detailed video for you all
on health insurance. In this video I will tell you
30 important points related to health insurance
in detail.
So in future whenever you buy any health
insurance policy,
always keep these important points in mind. When we
watch any investment video,
mostly we click on it many times and watch it,
but do not skip this health insurance video at
all because
if you
miss even one important point while buying health insurance, then
you may face a lot of problems in the future because of it.
Pawan sir has done this video. You also have to take health insurance.
[Music]
Ajay said
that
our number one point of the top ten points related to health insurance is the
claim settlement ratio. The
higher the claim settlement ratio, the better it will be considered,
but if the average
claim settlement ratio of a company is  If it is 95% or
more, it will be considered good. The
second point is the claim process. In this, you will
see that with how many hospitals the health insurance company is
empanelled for
cashless claims and of course, the
more hospitals that company is empanelled with
for cashless claims, the better it will be considered.
If a health insurance company
is empanelled with more than 80 hospitals for cashless claims, then it will be considered good.
Now, whenever you
buy a policy from any health insurance company, you
must check whether most of the major hospitals in the city you live in are
independent with that company for cashless claims or not. You
can check these details from that company's website.
Another important point of the claim process is
that you must check how long it takes for
your health insurance company to approve your cashless
plan.
The shorter the approval time of the Kepler scheme, the
better it will be for you because
until your cashless claim is approved by your health
insurance company, you will
not be able to be discharged from the hospital. So,
if any company  If your cashless claim
is approved within 1 or 2 hours, it will be
considered good. The
third thing you can keep in mind while purchasing a health insurance policy is whether
your health insurance
policy
provides the benefit of automatic restoration of sum assured.
Automatic restoration means that if I have
taken a family floater of the sum assured and if I suffer from any disease
due to which I have prepared a complete file
explanation, then if
I or my family members face
any problem in the future, can I
explain this file again or not? There are
very few companies in India that
provide the benefit of automatic restoration.
If any health insurance company is
providing this benefit, then
you must understand the benefit properly because this
benefit can be of many types and may
also have some limitations.
While studying the automatic restoration benefit, you
must keep these three things in mind: Number one,
this benefit is not applicable in any one year.  Will we
get unlimited or will there be any kind of restriction on it
Circle point Suppose
someone has a health cover of five plots
and the person gets a heart attack due to which
he claims a health cover of Rs 5 lakh completely
and after a few days, the next
day that person gets a heart attack again
but has the same disease, then will the person get the benefit of
this automatic restoration facility in this case
or not Hot
point Will this restoration benefit be
restored immediately after making any claim
or will it be restored after a few days
Suppose someone faces any problem and has taken the
complete sum assured
and within 1 month he again gets the same
problem, then will the
person get this restoration benefit in this case or
not Fourth point While buying a health insurance policy,
we should keep in mind whether there is
any glass of co-payment in this policy and also whether there is any
deduction on room rent in this policy for co-
payment  Class means that if
your policy has a 10% co-payment
clause, then if you have a claim of 1 lakh, then the
insurance company will offer only ₹93
and you will have to set the 8% (Rs. 10,000)
yourself. There are some
insurance plans in India in which co-
payment is allowed, which means
that the entire payment will be made by the health insurance company
and if any company is
providing such a benefit in its policy,
then naturally their premium amount will be a
little higher.
While buying a health insurance policy,
do check the capping of room rent. Most of the policies have
1% of sum assured room rent capping.
This means that if your term
loan is Rs. 5 lakh, then you
can take a room only up to half of this amount, i.e., ₹5,000. If
your room rent fee is more, then
whatever extra amount is there, you will have to
offer it yourself. This point is No Claim Bonus.
This means that if you have made any claim in any year.  If you have
not done so, then by how much amount will your sum assured increase this year?
If a company has a no-claim bonus of
25%, it means that if
you do not make any claim for four years,
your sum assured will double.
If you have time left to file and
you do not make any claim for four years, then
your sum assured will increase to
3 lakhs. Now, of course,
this sum assured will not increase by more than 100%.
The 6 points that you should keep in mind while buying a health insurance policy are the
period
clause. Before buying a health insurance policy,
if you have any disease, then we will
call it a pre-existing disease and
some insurance companies cover this pre-existing disease
after two, three or four years. So,
you
must check in your health insurance policy that after
how many years your policy covers these pre-existing diseases.
Now, the
shorter the period, the better it will be.
And the seventh important point is the
benefit of super top option.  If you already have an existing
lax cover and
want to increase it, you
can use the Super Top Up option. Super Top Up
means that someone has taken a ten-liter
car insurance and has
taken a 15x super top up on it. The
lax cover here is called a deductible. What this means is that
if a claim comes, the
work will be completed first from the stated lax amount. When the claim
amount exceeds ₹1 lakh, then your Super
Top Up policy will be activated. If an
amount goes for ventilator, then ₹10 will be deducted
from your best policy and ₹10 will be
deducted from your super top up policy.
An important point is that you must buy
sufficient health cover for yourself and your family
because medical expenses are
already quite high and it will increase
even more in the future. Even if your lawyer has
already given you a health cover,
you should still try to buy another health cover in
addition to this. It is fast when you  If you
change your job, the employer's cover will
not be available to you. Secondly, even when you retire, the
loyal cover will
not be available to you. It is difficult if the quality provided by your employer is
not sufficient. In that case, you should also
take a separate health insurance policy. How much health cover should we take? It will
vary from person to person, but at least we should
definitely take a cover of five to five plus, and on
top of that, we can take Super Top because the
premium there will be very useful. The 9th point
is the free and post hospitalization coverage
part. This means that will
our health
insurance policy cover our medical expenses before and after hospitalization or not?
Generally, the company provides a cover of Rs. 3068,
so you must check in your policy
that for how much
free and post hospitalization
coverage is your health insurance policy providing. Listen, and 10.1
I have implanted some more important points
which we should keep in mind.
While buying your policy, you
can check in your policy that your
policy is covering  Whether the policy provides free preventive health checkup
facility or not and if
you want your policy to
cover maternity expenses, then there are
some policies in India which
also cover maternity expenses.
In maternity expenses, you need to check
how much money the company will offer for maternity expenses
and also check in your policy whether
your policy is
covering procedures or not.
Procedure means that if
someone needs to undergo dialysis or
cataract operation, then dialysis
and cataract operations can be done within a few hours,
for this you do not need to have 24-hour access. So, will
your policy cover these procedures
and does your health insurance policy
provide online doctor consultation facility? While buying a health insurance policy,
you must keep one more very important
point in mind that if
you take Ayurvedic or homeopathic treatment, then is it covered in
your policy?
Under this, I will tell you about the
six QSP details of Novel Health Insurance, its
unique selling proposition, so that
we will know what is the
value proposition of this insurance company. The
number one USP is automatic
restoration of sum assured. The second USP
is no person standing on the front, there is no capping on
room rent for testing. Online doctor
consultation fee is the USP. The
insurance premium starts from just ₹50. The
contribution is very important.
Therefore, you can support your insurance policy
with this company and whenever you
support, the
waiting period of your existing businesses will be reduced
and at the same time,
you will get more cover at a relatively low premium. The
first reason why this health insurance policy named Sunna is good is that
Navel's cashless claim is provided
in about twenty minutes. The critical
point is their no claim bonus is twenty five
percent. There is no claim bonus for cashless claims
with 1000 hospitals in  You are empanelled. Fourth,
if the hospitalization is due to accidental injury, then the
injury
benefit will be doubled. Shift Navel Health
Insurance Company will provide you a per-slice plan
relationship manager and the
claim settlement ratio of this company is
1970 percent, which is of course good.
I have shared links related to health insurance in the description. By
clicking on those links, you will be
able to know the value proposition of this company in detail.
Sudharak video. If you liked this video, then
definitely like and share it and if
you have not yet subscribed to our YouTube channel, then
definitely
subscribe. Thanks a lot for watching.